learnvest.com 2015-12-07

# Privacy Policy | LearnVest

## Your Privacy Rights

LearnVest respects the privacy of our users and has developed this Privacy Policy to demonstrate its commitment to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy applies to LearnVest.com owned and operated by LearnVest (collectively, “We”, “Us” or “Our”). This Privacy Policy is intended to describe for you, as an individual who is a user of LearnVest.com or our services, the information we collect, how that information may be used, with whom it may be shared, and your choices about such uses and disclosures. We encourage you to read this Privacy Policy carefully when using our website or services or transacting business with us. By using our website, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. If you have any questions about our privacy practices, please refer to the end of this Privacy Policy for information on how to contact us.

The TRUSTe program only covers information that is collected through this website, [http://www.learnvest.com](http://www.learnvest.com/), and information that may be collected through our mobile website and Mobile Application (App). In order to view our relationship with TRUSTe please visit the validation page visible by clicking on the TRUSTe seal. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

## Information we collect about you

### In General

We may collect personal information that can identify you, such as your name and e-mail address, and other information that does not identify you. When you provide personal information through our website, the information may be sent to servers located in the United States and other countries around the world.

  * Information you provide. We may collect and store any personal information you enter on our website or provide to us in some other manner. This includes identifying information, such as your name, address, e-mail address, and telephone number, and, if you transact business with us, financial information such as your payment method (valid credit card number, type, expiration date, or other financial information). We also may request information about your interests and activities, your gender and age, your financial life and other demographic information, as well as public information such as user ratings, reviews and comments, and other information you view or contribute to the website.
  * If you choose to use LearnVest’s My Money Center (on the web or via the App), we will request usernames and passwords in order to access information as it relates to your bank account, credit cards, investment account, or loans. LearnVest does not store your usernames or passwords for financial institutions on its servers.
  * Information from other sources. We may also periodically obtain both personal and non-personal information about you from other business partners, contractors, and other third parties, such as the U.S. Postal Service, to verify your address so we can properly ship your order and prevent fraud. Examples of information that we may receive include: updated delivery and address information, purchase history, and additional demographic information.
  * When you download and use our App, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operating system version, and the device identifier (or “UDID”). We collect your location-based information for the purpose of [locating a place that you may be searching for in your area]. We will only share this information with our mapping provider for the sole purpose of providing you the service. If you want to stop the automatic collection of your location information, you may do so by accessing the privacy settings in the app and/or on your device and/or by uninstalling the app. We do not send push notifications to your device.

### Use of cookies and other technologies to collect information

We use various technologies to collect information from your computer and about your activities on our site.

  * Log Files. As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.
  * Technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags, and scripts are used by LearnVest and our third party marketing partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.
  * We use cookies to remember users’ settings (e.g. language preference) and for authentication _._ Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.
  * We use Local Storage, such as HTML5, to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our website or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity also use Flash cookies and HTML5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5. To manage Flash cookies, please click here: <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html>
  * We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and web beacons to collect non-personal information about your activities on this and other websites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.
  * Some of our pages utilize framing techniques to serve content from our partners while preserving the look and feel of our site. Please be aware that you are providing your personal information to these third parties and not to LearnVest.
  * Mobile Analytics. We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Mobile Software on your phone, tablet, or other device. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and from where the application was downloaded. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personal information you submit within the mobile application.

## How we use the information we collect

### In General

We may use information that we collect about you to:

  * Deliver the products and services that you have requested;
  * Manage your account and provide you with customer support;
  * Perform research and analysis about your use of, or interest in, our products, services, or content, or products, services, or content offered by others;
  * Aggregate data such as the anonymous personal financial data you may enter into our tools. This aggregate information does not identify particular users or otherwise allow anyone to recover sensitive information about individual users. Aggregate information belongs to LearnVest, and is not subject to this Privacy Policy;
  * Communicate with you by e-mail, postal mail, telephone and/or mobile devices about products or services that may be of interest to you either from us or third parties;
  * Develop and display content and advertising tailored to your interests on our site and other sites;
  * Verify your eligibility and deliver prizes in connection with contests and sweepstakes;
  * Enforce our terms and conditions;
  * Manage our business; and
  * Perform functions as otherwise described to you at the time of collection.

### How we protect your personal information

We take appropriate security measures (including physical, electronic and procedural measures) to help safeguard your personal information from unauthorized access and disclosure. For example, only authorized employees are permitted to access personal information, and they may do so only for permitted business functions. In addition, we use encryption in the transmission of your sensitive personal information (such as credit card number and/or geo-location data) between your system and ours, we encrypt the transmission of that information using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology, and we also use anti-virus software and firewalls to help prevent unauthorized persons from gaining access to your personal information. We want you to feel confident using our website to transact business. However, no system can be completely secure. Therefore, although we take steps to secure your information, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information, searches, or other communications will always remain secure. Users should also take care with how they handle and disclose their personal information and should avoid sending personal information through insecure e-mail, such as bank account numbers, social security numbers, etc. Notably, LearnVest does not require, request or otherwise collect users’ social security number under any circumstances and we encourage you not to voluntarily share your social security number to LearnVest whether by e-mail, on the website or on any other media. If you have any questions about security on our website, you can contact us at [feedback@learnvest.com](mailto:feedback@learnvest.com).

## We may share personal information

We want you to understand when and with whom we may share personal or other information we have collected about you or your activities on our website or while using our services.

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this Privacy Policy.  **We do not sell your personal information to third parties.**

### We may share personal information with:

  * Authorized service providers: We may share your personal information with our authorized service providers that perform certain services on our behalf. These services may include processing credit card payments, providing customer service and marketing assistance, performing business and sales analysis, supporting our website functionality, and supporting contests, sweepstakes, surveys and other features offered through our website. These service providers may have access to personal information needed to perform their functions but are not permitted to share or use such information for any other purposes.
  * Other Situations. We also may disclose your information: 
    * ­For our premium members, we may share information with affiliated financial companies with whom we may market products jointly.
    * ­In response to a subpoena, bankruptcy proceedings or similar investigative demand, a court order, or a request for cooperation from law enforcement or other government or regulatory agency; to establish or exercise our legal rights; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law. In such cases, we may raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us.
    * ­When we believe disclosure is appropriate in connection with efforts to investigate, prevent, or take other action regarding illegal activity, suspected fraud or other wrongdoing; to protect and defend the rights, property or safety of our company, our users, our employees, or others; to comply with applicable law or cooperate with law enforcement; or to enforce our website terms and conditions or other agreements or policies.
  * If LearnVest is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via e-mail and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.
  * To any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

## Third Parties

Any third parties to whom we may disclose personal information may have their own privacy policies which describe how they use and disclose personal information. Those policies will govern use, handling, and disclosure of your personal information once we have shared it with those third parties as described in this Privacy Policy. If you want to learn more about their privacy practices, we encourage you to visit the websites of those third parties. These entities or their servers may be located either inside or outside the United States.

### Third-Party websites

There are a number of places on our website where you may click on a link to access other websites that do not operate under this Privacy Policy. For example, if you click on an advertisement or a search result on our website, you may be taken to a website that we do not control. These third-party websites may independently solicit and collect information, including personal information, from you and, in some instances, provide us with information about your activities on those websites. We recommend that you consult the privacy policies of all third-party websites you visit by clicking on the “privacy” link typically located at the bottom of the webpage you are visiting.

### No Rights of Third Parties

This Privacy Policy does not create rights enforceable by third parties or require disclosure of any personal information relating to users of the website.

## How you can access your information

If you have an online account with us, you have the ability to review and update or delete your personal information online by logging into your account using the Login link at the upper right side of the page. You can also review and update your personal information by contacting us at [feedback@learnvest.com](mailto:feedback@learnvest.com) or by contacting us by U.S. mail at the contact information listed below. You may also choose to close your account by e-mailing us at [feedback@learnvest.com](mailto:feedback@learnvest.com). We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

After you close your account, you will not be able to sign in to our website or access any of your personal information. However, you can open a new account at any time. If you close your account, we may still retain certain information associated with your account (including geo-location data) for analytical purposes and recordkeeping integrity, as well as to prevent fraud, enforce our terms and conditions, take actions we deem necessary to protect the integrity of our website or our users, or take other actions otherwise permitted by law. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us at [feedback@learnvest.com](mailto:feedback@learnvest.com). In addition, if certain information has already been provided to third parties as described in this Privacy Policy, retention of that information will be subject to those third parties’ policies.

## Your choices about collection and use of your information

  * You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but that may result in your being unable to use certain features of our website because such information may be required in order for you to register as a member; participate in a contest, promotion, survey, or sweepstakes; ask a question; rate, review or comment on articles and merchants; or initiate other transactions on our website.
  * You will be given the opportunity, in any commercial e-mail that we send to you, to opt out of receiving such messages in the future. It may take up to 10 business days for us to process an opt-out request. We may send you other types of transactional and relationship e-mail communications, such as service announcements, administrative notices, and surveys, without offering you the opportunity to opt out of receiving them. Please note that changing information in your account, or otherwise opting out of receipt of promotional e-mail communications will only affect future activities or communications from us. If we have already provided your information to a third party (such as an event provider) before you have changed your preferences or updated your information, you may have to change your preferences directly with that third party.

## Choice/Opt-Out

You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing e-mails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these e-mails or you can contact us at [feedback@learnvest.com](mailto:feedback@learnvest.com).

## Invite-A-Friend

You can import contacts from your Outlook or other e-mail account address book to tell a friend about our website using a third party service provider. If you choose to use this feature, we do not store your usernames or passwords.  
If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our website, we will ask you for your friend’s name and e-mail address. We will automatically send your friend an e-mail inviting him or her to visit the website. We will also send a one-time reminder e-mail if he or she has not created an account within 7 days. LearnVest stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time e-mail and for tracking the success of our referral program.  
Your friend may contact us at [feedback@learnvest.com](mailto:feedback@learnvest.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

## Job applicants

If your personal information is submitted through our website when applying for a position with our company, the information will be used solely in connection with considering and acting upon your application. We may retain your personal information for a period of time, but only for the purpose of considering your application for current or future available positions. This information may be shared with third-party service providers retained by us to collect, maintain, and analyze candidate submissions for job postings.  
Please refer to “Your choices about collection and use of your information.”

## Blogs, bulletin boards, reviews, and chat rooms

We may provide areas on our websites where you can post information about yourself and others; communicate with others; post reviews of products, establishments, and the like; and upload content (e.g. pictures, videos, audio files, etc.). Our blog is hosted and managed by a third party application called Disqus, which may require you to register to post a comment. In addition, such postings may appear on other websites or when searches are executed on the subject of your posting. Also, whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information on publicly viewable webpages, that information will be publicly available and can be collected and used by others. For example, if you post your e-mail address, you may receive unsolicited messages. We cannot control who reads your posting or what other users may do with the information you voluntarily post, so we encourage you to exercise discretion and caution with respect to your personal information. We do not have access or control of the information posted to the blog. You will need to contact or login into the third-party application if you want the personal information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third-party application uses your information, please review their privacy policy.

## Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA)

We are committed to protecting the privacy of children. Visitors under 13 years of age are not permitted to use and/or submit their personal information at any Site. We do not knowingly solicit or collect information from visitors under 13 years of age. If we obtain actual knowledge that we have collected personal information about an individual under 13 years of age, that information will be immediately deleted from our website. We encourage parents and guardians to spend time online with their children and to participate and monitor the interactive activities of their children.

## Social Media Widgets

Our website includes Social Media Features and Widgets, such as the Share button or interactive mini-programs that run on our website. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## Visiting our websites from outside the United States

This Privacy Policy is intended to cover collection of information on our website from residents of the United States. If you are visiting our website from outside the United States, please be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States where our servers are located and our central database is operated. The data protection and other laws of the United States and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country. Please be assured that we seek to take reasonable steps to ensure that your privacy is protected. By using our services, you understand that your information may be transferred to our facilities and those third parties with whom we share it as described in this Privacy Policy.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

We will occasionally update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in our practices and services. When we post changes to this Privacy Policy, we will revise the “last updated” date at the bottom of this document. If we make any material changes in the way we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will notify you by sending an e-mail to the e-mail address you most recently provided us in your account, profile, or registration (unless we do not have such an e-mail address), and/or by prominently posting notice of the changes on our website prior to the change becoming effective. We recommend that you check our website from time to time to inform yourself of any changes in this Privacy Policy or any of our other policies.

## How to contact us

****If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or our information-handling practices, or if you would like to request information about our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes, please contact us by e-mail or postal mail as follows:

**Privacy Department**  
LearnVest, Inc.  
113 University Place, 5th floor  
New York, NY 10003

## Linked Financial Information

### ****Cookies

****A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record keeping purposes. Cookies can be either session cookies or persistent cookies. A session cookie expires when you close your browser and is used to make it easier for you to navigate our website. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. For example, when you sign in to our website, we will record your user or member ID and the name on your user or member profile in the cookie file on your computer. We also may record your password in this cookie file, if you indicated that you would like your password saved for automatic sign-in. For security purposes, we will encrypt any usernames, passwords, and other user or member account-related data that we store in such cookies. In the case of sites and services that do not use a user or member ID, the cookie will contain a unique identifier. We may allow our authorized service providers to serve cookies from our website to allow them to assist us in various activities, such as doing analysis and research on the effectiveness of our website, content and advertising. You may delete or decline cookies by changing your browser settings. (Click “Help” in the toolbar of most browsers for instructions.) If you do so, some of the features and services of our website may not function properly. We may allow third parties, including advertising companies, and ad networks, to display advertisements on our website. These companies may use tracking technologies, such as cookies, to collect information about users who view or interact with their advertisements. Our website does not provide any personal information to these third parties, but they may collect information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw and/or clicked on the advertisements they deliver, and possibly associate this information with your subsequent visits to the advertised websites. They also may combine this information with personal information they collect from you. The collection and use of that information is subject to the third-party’s privacy policy. This information allows them to deliver targeted advertisements and gauge their effectiveness. Some of these third-party advertising companies may be advertising networks that are members of the Network Advertising Initiative, which offers a single location to opt out of ad targeting from member companies ([ www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)).

### Web Beacons

Web beacons (also known as clear gifs, pixel tags or web bugs) are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of web users or to access cookies. Unlike cookies, which are stored on the user’s computer hard drive, web beacons are embedded invisibly on the web pages (or in e-mail) and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. Web beacons may be used to deliver or communicate with cookies, to count users who have visited certain pages and to understand usage patterns. We also may receive an anonymous identification number if you come to our website from an online advertisement displayed on a third-party website.

## Third party collection and use of your data

When you use or connect to a LearnVest website or download a LearnVest App by or through a Third Party Platform, such as Facebook or other social networking website, you allow us to access and/or collect certain information from your Third Party Platform profile/account (such as your Facebook account) or via any cookies placed on your device by such Third Party Platform as permitted by the terms of the agreement and your privacy settings with the Third Party Platform. We will share such information with the Third Party Platform for their use as permitted by the terms of the agreement and your privacy setting with the Third Party Platform.

We will share some of the information we collect from you upon install of the App with vendors and other service providers who are engaged by or working with us in connection with the operation of the services we provide to you and/or for analytics purposes, which may require the reproduction and display of such information in an aggregated and anonymized manner such that will not identify you in any way.

You may “opt out” of the collection of your information for third party analytics purposes by following the directions provided by our third party analytics vendor located at [www.mobileapptracking.com/privacy-policy](http://www.mobileapptracking.com/privacy-policy/). If you “opt out” with our third party analytics provider, that action is specific to the information we collect specifically for that provider and does not limit our ability to collect information from you, under the terms of this privacy policy, for other vendors.

_Last Updated: October 13, 2015_
